<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<railwayInfo>
    <history>
        <events>
    <event>
        <date>1830</date>
        <description>The Liverpool and Manchester Railway opens, marking the debut of George Stephenson's groundbreaking locomotive, "The Rocket," setting new standards for speed and efficiency in railway travel.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>1837</date>
        <description>The Grand Junction Railway, the world's first long-distance railway, is opened in England, connecting Birmingham to Warrington.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>1848</date>
        <description>The first railway to span a nation, the Great Indian Peninsula Railway, begins operations in India, significantly enhancing transportation across the subcontinent.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>1869</date>
        <description>The completion of the First Transcontinental Railroad in the United States, linking the east and west coasts and revolutionizing travel and commerce across the country.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>1883</date>
        <description>The American Railway Association introduces standard time zones, allowing for consistent schedules and timetables across the expanding railway network.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>1889</date>
        <description>The inauguration of the Forth Railway Bridge in Scotland, a pioneering steel structure and a symbol of engineering excellence in railway infrastructure.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>1923</date>
        <description>The formation of the "Big Four" railway companies in the United Kingdom following the grouping of various smaller companies, leading to more efficient management and operations.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>1934</date>
        <description>The introduction of the streamlined "Flying Scotsman" train service in the United Kingdom, exemplifying speed and modern design in railway travel.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>1955</date>
        <description>The introduction of Japan's high-speed "Shinkansen" bullet train, setting new standards for speed, safety, and comfort in rail transportation.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>1981</date>
        <description>The opening of France's TGV (Train à Grande Vitesse), Europe's first high-speed rail service, revolutionizing travel on the continent.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>2007</date>
        <description>China debuts its high-speed rail system, showcasing technological advancements and rapidly expanding the world's largest network of high-speed trains.</description>
    </event>
    <event>
        <date>2021</date>
        <description>Continued advancements in railway technology include the development of maglev trains and further expansion of high-speed rail networks worldwide, emphasizing sustainability and efficiency in modern transportation systems.</description>
    </event>
</events>

        <!-- Add more historical events -->
    </history>
    <interestingFacts>
        <fact>
            <title>Longest Railway</title>
            <description>The Trans-Siberian Railway is the world's longest railway, spanning approximately 9,289 kilometers.</description>
        </fact>
        <fact>
            <title>High-Speed Train</title>
            <description>The Shinkansen in Japan is one of the fastest trains in the world, reaching speeds of up to 320 km/h.</description>
        </fact>
        <!-- Add more interesting facts -->
    </interestingFacts>
    <trainModels>
        <model>
            <name>ICE 4</name>
            <description>The Intercity-Express 4 is a high-speed train operated in Germany and other European countries.</description>
        </model>
        <model>
            <name>Maglev</name>
            <description>Magnetic levitation trains use magnetic fields for propulsion, achieving high speeds with minimal friction.</description>
        </model>
        <!-- Add more train models -->
    </trainModels>
</railwayInfo>
